<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<rss xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/" xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Iraqi News</title>
    <atom:link href="https://www.iraqinews.com/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <link>https://www.iraqinews.com/</link>
    <description/>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 21:13:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
    <sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
    <generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.6.2</generator>
    <image>
      <url>https://www.iraqinews.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/11/cropped-favico-32x32.png</url>
      <title>Iraqi News</title>
      <link>https://www.iraqinews.com/</link>
      <width>32</width>
      <height>32</height>
    </image>
    <item>
      <title>Iraq launches massive 5 Billion Dinar grant to boost cinema</title>
      <link>https://www.iraqinews.com/iraq/iraq-film-funding-sudani-initiative-cannes-selection/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[
Jawad Al-Samarraie
]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 21:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[
Iraq
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
Ahmed Fakak Al-Badrani
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
Cannes Film Festival Iraq
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
Iraq film grant
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
Iraqi cinema funding
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
Iraqi Cinema Initiative
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
Iraqi culture support
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
Iraqi filmmakers
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
Iraqi films 2025
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
Mohammed Shia Al Sudani cinema
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
VOX Cinemas Dijlah Village
]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.iraqinews.com/?p=209320</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[

<p>Baghdad (IraqiNews.com) – In a major boost for the nation&#8217;s film industry, Iraq&#8217;s Minister of Culture, Tourism, and Antiquities, Ahmed Fakak Al-Badrani, announced the launch of a significant grant initiated [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.iraqinews.com/iraq/iraq-film-funding-sudani-initiative-cannes-selection/">Iraq launches massive 5 Billion Dinar grant to boost cinema</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.iraqinews.com">Iraqi News</a>.</p>

]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<p>Baghdad (IraqiNews.com) – In a major boost for the nation&#8217;s film industry, Iraq&#8217;s Minister of Culture, Tourism, and Antiquities, Ahmed Fakak Al-Badrani, announced the launch of a significant grant initiated by Prime Minister Mohammed Shia Al Sudani. The grant, totaling 5.17 billion Iraqi dinars (approx. $4 million USD), aims to support and revitalize Iraqi cinema through the &#8220;Iraqi Cinema Initiative&#8221;.</p>



<p>The announcement came during a press conference on Monday, April 21st, at VOX Cinemas in Dijlah Village, attended by cultural advisors, officials like Dr. Arif Al-Saadi and Dr. Jabbar Joudi, and prominent artists. Minister Al-Badrani praised the Prime Minister&#8217;s commitment to Iraqi culture and cinema.</p>



<p>Following a nine-month selection process involving 376 submissions from across Iraq, 86 films were chosen for the grant&#8217;s shortlist, spanning narrative features, documentaries, shorts, and post-production projects. Highlighting the initiative&#8217;s ambition, several feature films, including &#8220;The Possessed&#8221; (Al-Mamsous) by Ali Shmeil and &#8220;The President&#8217;s Cake&#8221; (Ka&#8217;akat Al-Ra&#8217;ees), were announced as Iraq&#8217;s official representation at the prestigious Cannes Film Festival.</p>



<p>Officials stated the grant aims to foster new filmmaking talent throughout Iraq and support projects that document Iraqi reality. This substantial investment signals a hopeful new chapter for Iraqi cinema on both national and international stages.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.iraqinews.com/iraq/iraq-film-funding-sudani-initiative-cannes-selection/">Iraq launches massive 5 Billion Dinar grant to boost cinema</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.iraqinews.com">Iraqi News</a>.</p>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>US dollar exchange rate drops in Baghdad, rises in Erbil</title>
      <link>https://www.iraqinews.com/iraq/us-dollar-exchange-rate-drops-in-baghdad-rises-in-erbil/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[
Amr Salem
]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 19:45:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[
Iraq
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
Baghdad
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
CBI
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
Central Bank of Iraq
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
Erbil
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
Exchange Rate
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
Iraqi dinar
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
parallel market
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
US dollar
]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.iraqinews.com/?p=209315</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[

<p>Baghdad (IraqiNews.com) – The exchange rate for the US dollar compared to the Iraqi dinar declined on Tuesday in Baghdad and rose in the capital of Iraqi Kurdistan, Erbil. The [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.iraqinews.com/iraq/us-dollar-exchange-rate-drops-in-baghdad-rises-in-erbil/">US dollar exchange rate drops in Baghdad, rises in Erbil</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.iraqinews.com">Iraqi News</a>.</p>

]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<p>Baghdad (IraqiNews.com) – The exchange rate for the US dollar compared to the Iraqi dinar declined on Tuesday in Baghdad and rose in the capital of Iraqi Kurdistan, Erbil.</p>



<p>The US dollar exchange rate declined in Baghdad’s Al-Kifah and Al-Harithiya stock exchanges, reaching 1,457 Iraqi dinars compared to 1,459 Iraqi dinars on Tuesday morning.</p>



<p>The exchange rate in currency exchange shops in Baghdad ranged between 1,467.5 dinars and 1,447.5 dinars, Shafaq News reported.</p>



<p>In Erbil, the US dollar exchange rate increased, fluctuating between 1,462 and 1,461 Iraqi dinars.</p>



<p>The Central Bank of Iraq (CBI) said in February 2023 that it has begun using the new US dollar exchange rate of 1,300 dinars to every US dollar.</p>



<p>The previous official exchange rate was 1,450 dinars to one US dollar, which was being exchanged in the parallel market at a rate of 1,550 dinars.</p>



<p>While the official exchange rate was 1,450 dinars per dollar in January 2023, the US currency was being exchanged at 1,610 dinars during the same month in the parallel market in Iraq. This variation represented a more than 10 percent difference in exchange rates.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.iraqinews.com/iraq/us-dollar-exchange-rate-drops-in-baghdad-rises-in-erbil/">US dollar exchange rate drops in Baghdad, rises in Erbil</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.iraqinews.com">Iraqi News</a>.</p>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iraq adds 80 million cubic feet of gas to national output</title>
      <link>https://www.iraqinews.com/iraq/iraq-adds-80-million-cubic-feet-of-gas-to-national-output/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[
Amr Salem
]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 19:30:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[
Iraq
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
Basrah Gas Company
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
BGC
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
BP
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
British Petroleum
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
electrical grid
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
Gas
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
gas production
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
Majnoon field
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
Rumaila
]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.iraqinews.com/?p=209313</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[

<p>Baghdad (IraqiNews.com) – The production capacity of the Basrah Gas Company (BGC) has been significantly increased, with the addition of 80 million standard cubic feet of gas. The development is [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.iraqinews.com/iraq/iraq-adds-80-million-cubic-feet-of-gas-to-national-output/">Iraq adds 80 million cubic feet of gas to national output</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.iraqinews.com">Iraqi News</a>.</p>

]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<p>Baghdad (IraqiNews.com) – The production capacity of the Basrah Gas Company (BGC) has been significantly increased, with the addition of 80 million standard cubic feet of gas.</p>



<p>The development is part of a larger plan to increase energy production in southern Iraq in response to growing demand for power.</p>



<p>In a statement to the Iraqi News Agency (INA), BGC&#8217;s Deputy Director, Marfa Kadhim Al-Asadi, highlighted that the company&#8217;s strategic focus is on investments in the gas sector.</p>



<p>Under the first licensing round, BGC is in charge of running three important fields in southern Iraq, and the company is dedicated to optimizing gas collection over the next three years, according to Al-Asadi.</p>



<p>Al-Asadi clarified that BGC is adhering to a comprehensive strategy to handle the difficulties that the power industry is likely to face this summer.</p>



<p>GBC has collaborated effectively with field operators like British Petroleum (BP) and other partners to expedite projects that can boost gas production, according to Al-Asadi.</p>



<p>BGC has completed several significant initiatives in 2024 and is now getting set for 2025. According to Al-Asadi, some initiatives that were originally planned for the end of 2025 will be finished within the next couple of months.</p>



<p>The recent increase in output is anticipated to be mostly due to two important initiatives. According to Al-Asadi, the South Rumaila gas desalination project will add 40 million cubic feet, and another 40 million cubic feet will be added from the Majnoon field.</p>



<p>Additionally, Al-Asadi affirmed that the national electrical grid will get a share of this additional supply.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.iraqinews.com/iraq/iraq-adds-80-million-cubic-feet-of-gas-to-national-output/">Iraq adds 80 million cubic feet of gas to national output</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.iraqinews.com">Iraqi News</a>.</p>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iraq plans to increase trade exchange with Turkey</title>
      <link>https://www.iraqinews.com/iraq/iraq-plans-to-increase-trade-exchange-with-turkey/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[
Amr Salem
]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 14:48:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[
Iraq
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
trade exchange
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
Turkey
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
Turkish companies
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
world economy
]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.iraqinews.com/?p=209311</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[

<p>Baghdad (IraqiNews.com) – The spokesperson for the Iraqi Ministry of Trade, Mohamed Hanoun, revealed on Monday that there is an Iraqi-Turkish desire to increase the volume of economic and trade [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.iraqinews.com/iraq/iraq-plans-to-increase-trade-exchange-with-turkey/">Iraq plans to increase trade exchange with Turkey</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.iraqinews.com">Iraqi News</a>.</p>

]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<p>Baghdad (IraqiNews.com) – The spokesperson for the Iraqi Ministry of Trade, Mohamed Hanoun, revealed on Monday that there is an Iraqi-Turkish desire to increase the volume of economic and trade exchange, which has surpassed $14 billion, according to statistics released by the Turkish Ministry of Trade.</p>



<p>In a statement to the Iraqi News Agency (INA), Hanoun indicated that the volume of trade exchange is steadily growing given Turkey&#8217;s position in the world economy.</p>



<p>To create a comprehensive strategy that incorporates new processes that support the growth of ties between the two countries, the Iraqi Ministry of Trade has coordinated with all government sectors and agencies.</p>



<p>The Turkish Minister of Foreign Affairs, Hakan Fidan, confirmed in January that the volume of trade exchange between Iraq and Turkey reached $20 billion.</p>



<p>In a joint press conference with Iraqi Foreign Minister Fuad Hussein, Fidan said that Turkey sees its relationship with Iraq as crucial, indicating that Turkey will experience more security and stability the more Iraq does.</p>



<p>The Turkish Minister of Trade, Omer Bolat, said in early December that his country seeks to increase trade exchange with Iraq to $30 billion.</p>



<p>Bolat added that Turkish companies and investors have completed projects in Iraq worth $35 billion.</p>



<p>Turkey’s trade minister also revealed that he reached an agreement with Iraqi officials to increase trade exchange between the two countries.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.iraqinews.com/iraq/iraq-plans-to-increase-trade-exchange-with-turkey/">Iraq plans to increase trade exchange with Turkey</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.iraqinews.com">Iraqi News</a>.</p>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kuwaiti emir invited to Arab Summit in Iraq</title>
      <link>https://www.iraqinews.com/iraq/kuwaiti-emir-invited-to-arab-summit-in-iraq/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[
Amr Salem
]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 13:23:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[
Iraq
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
America
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
Arab League
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
Arab summit
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
Baghdad
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
Iran
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
Kuwait
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
Syria
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
the United States
]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.iraqinews.com/?p=209308</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[

<p>Baghdad (IraqiNews.com) – The Iraqi Minister of Foreign Affairs, Fuad Hussein, invited Kuwaiti Emir Sheikh Meshal Al-Ahmad Al-Jaber Al-Sabah on Tuesday to participate in the Arab Summit, which will take [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.iraqinews.com/iraq/kuwaiti-emir-invited-to-arab-summit-in-iraq/">Kuwaiti emir invited to Arab Summit in Iraq</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.iraqinews.com">Iraqi News</a>.</p>

]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<p>Baghdad (IraqiNews.com) – The Iraqi Minister of Foreign Affairs, Fuad Hussein, invited Kuwaiti Emir Sheikh Meshal Al-Ahmad Al-Jaber Al-Sabah on Tuesday to participate in the Arab Summit, which will take place in the Iraqi capital, Baghdad, next month.</p>



<p>During his meeting with Kuwaiti Crown Prince Sheikh Sabah Khaled Al-Hamad Al-Sabah in Kuwait, Hussein delivered an official invitation from Iraqi President Abdul Latif Jamal Rashid to Sheikh Meshal to participate in the Arab Summit scheduled for May 17 in Baghdad, according to a statement released by the Iraqi Foreign Ministry.</p>



<p>Al-Sabah emphasized the need for concerted efforts to enhance coordinated Arab action, pointing to the crucial role Iraq played as a founding member of the Arab League.</p>



<p>Hussein clarified that Iraq anticipates the Kuwaiti leaders&#8217; participation in the next summit, pointing out that it coincides with an important phase as the Arab world faces significant challenges.</p>



<p>The meeting further addressed measures to improve the two countries&#8217; bilateral cooperation in the areas of politics, economy, and culture.</p>



<p>The two parties discussed the most significant regional and international developments, emphasizing the value of coordinated efforts to address present issues in a way that benefits the people in both countries and advances regional security and stability.</p>



<p>Hussein said that Iraq is keeping a close eye on the United States-Iran discussions and hopes they will be successful, adding that Iraq is eager to assist the process in any way it can.</p>



<p>In May 2024, Rashid said that Iraq will host the next Arab summit after Syria declined to host the event.</p>



<p>Rashid’s statement took place during his speech at the 33<sup>rd</sup> summit of the Arab League held in the Bahraini capital, Manama, according to the Iraqi Presidency.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.iraqinews.com/iraq/kuwaiti-emir-invited-to-arab-summit-in-iraq/">Kuwaiti emir invited to Arab Summit in Iraq</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.iraqinews.com">Iraqi News</a>.</p>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Iraq’s Central Bank restricts bank cards usage abroad</title>
      <link>https://www.iraqinews.com/iraq/iraqs-central-bank-restricts-bank-cards-usage-abroad/</link>
      <dc:creator><![CDATA[
Amr Salem
]]></dc:creator>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 05:05:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <category><![CDATA[
Iraq
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
bank cards
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
CBI
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
Central Bank of Iaq
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
debit cards
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
financial transactions
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
foreign currencies
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
merchants
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
pensioners
]]></category>
      <category><![CDATA[
US dollar
]]></category>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.iraqinews.com/?p=209278</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[

<p>Baghdad (IraqiNews.com) – The Central Bank of Iraq (CBI) released an explanation on Monday concerning the usage of both credit and debit cards outside of Iraq, including the monthly cap [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.iraqinews.com/iraq/iraqs-central-bank-restricts-bank-cards-usage-abroad/">Iraq’s Central Bank restricts bank cards usage abroad</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.iraqinews.com">Iraqi News</a>.</p>

]]></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[

<p>Baghdad (IraqiNews.com) – The Central Bank of Iraq (CBI) released an explanation on Monday concerning the usage of both credit and debit cards outside of Iraq, including the monthly cap for travel and medical treatment.</p>



<p>According to a statement released by the CBI, the basic monthly limit for using credit or debit cards outside of Iraq was $5,000 or the equivalent in foreign currencies per card, Shafaq News reported.</p>



<p>The monthly cap for pensioners was increased to $10,000 or its foreign currency equivalent.</p>



<p>According to the CBI, the monthly limit was increased to $20,000 only for transactions made by merchants, whereas the monthly cap for medical treatment was increased to $50,000.</p>



<p>The step aims to improve international transaction control and guarantee the security of future expansion in international financial transactions. </p>



<p>Additionally, the action seeks to restrict the movement of foreign currencies out of Iraq, especially US dollars.</p>
<p>The post <a href="https://www.iraqinews.com/iraq/iraqs-central-bank-restricts-bank-cards-usage-abroad/">Iraq’s Central Bank restricts bank cards usage abroad</a> appeared first on <a href="https://www.iraqinews.com">Iraqi News</a>.</p>

]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
